animation it's the change from one CSS style to another over the dimension of
动画它是在时间维度上从一种 CSS 样式到另一种 CSS 样式的
time every animation has at least two states a starting point and an ending
变化每个动画至少有两个状态
point when you move from start to finish CSS will calculate all the values in
当你从开始到结束移动时的起点和终点CSS 将
between in computer science this is called inbetweening or a tween animation
计算计算机科学中的所有值这被称为 中间或补间动画
imagine we have an element that we want to fade in over a duration of one second
假设我们有一个元素，我们想要在动画开始时在一秒钟内淡入，
when the animation starts the browser calculates a new a pasty value for every
浏览器为渲染的每一帧计算一个新的粘贴值
frame rendered and it does so using a linear timing function which means the
，它使用线性计时函数来计算，这意味着
amount of change that occurs to the CSS value is exactly the same for each unit
CSS 值发生的变化量对于每个单位时间是完全相同的
of time but in the real physical world things rarely move at a perfect linear
，但在现实物理世界中，很少以完美的线性速度移动，
pace things ease in ease out and change the velocity gracefully you can do the
事情会缓和缓出并优雅地改变速度，您可以
same in your CSS animations by providing a timing function there are many
在 CSS 中做同样的事情 通过提供计时功能来制作动画 有许多
built-in functions where you can define your own custom veggie acres the easiest
内置功能，您可以在其中定义自己的自定义蔬菜英亩
way to create an animation with CSS is with a transition start by adding the
使用 CSS 创建动画的最简单方法是通过将
transition property to a selector the first value is the property that you
转换属性添加到选择器开始转换，第一个值是您
want to animate in our case its opacity the second value is the duration you can
要在我们的例子中设置动画的属性，它的不透明度第二个值是您
define it in seconds or milliseconds now whenever the opacity for this element
现在可以在此元素的不透明度更改时以秒或毫秒为单位定义它的持续时间
changes CSS will automatically handle the animation for you for example we can
CSS 将自动为您处理动画，例如我们可以
target the hover pseudo selector and change the opacity to one and that's all
定位悬停伪选择器并将不透明度更改为 1，这就是使用 CSS
it takes to create a fade-in fade-out animation with CSS we can refine this
创建淡入淡出动画所需的全部内容，我们可以
animation by adding an additional value for a delay or a timing function use a
通过添加附加值来优化此动画对于延迟或计时功能，请使用
built-in easing function or create your own custom as the a curve but what if
内置的缓动功能或创建自己的自定义曲线作为曲线，但如果
you want to animate something forever or in multiple steps keyframes allow you to
您想永久或分多个步骤制作动画怎么办？关键帧允许您
define animations independent of a selector first give your keyframe
定义独立于选择器的动画首先给您的关键帧
animation a name then define your starting styles with from and your
动画一个名称，然后用 from 定义您的起始样式，
ending styles with to any intermediate styles or steps in the animation can be
用 to 定义您的结束样式，动画中的任何中间样式或步骤可以
defined as a percentage in relative time to the starting point if your animation
定义为如果您的动画
is 4 seconds long then 25% would be 1 second into that animation you can use
长度为 4 秒，则相对于起点的时间百分比，然后 25% 将是该动画的 1 秒，您可以
this animation by referencing it as the animation name in one of your selectors
通过在其中一个选择器中将其引用为动画名称来使用此动画，
give it a duration and timing function then change the iteration count to
为其提供持续时间和计时功能然后将迭代次数更改为
infinite to make it loop forever this has been CSS animation in 100 seconds
无限，使其永远循环这已经是 100 秒内的 CSS 动画
hit the like button if you want to see more short videos like this thanks for
如果您想看更多这样的短视频，请点击“赞”按钮，谢谢
watching and I will see you in the next one
观看，我会在下一个视频中见到你
you